Luke Lewandowski

Head of Development and Quality Assurance

about

Sydney, Australia

□ luke@
lewandowskis.com

+61-403-018-388

• lemining

languages

English & Polish

legal

Legally able to work in Australia, New Zealand & EU.

industries

Media Construction Retail/E-Commerce

programming

C# Python Lua TypeScript/JavaScript

dev

micro-services ci/cd kubernetes/ECS event-bus automation

cloud

AWS GCP Azure Rackspace

summary

I'm a goal oriented professional with a consistent record of exceeding performance expectations.

Most recently I have been involved in digital transformations of large non-digital businesses to fulfil on their digital strategies resulting in extra revenue streams as well as increasing digital awareness throughout the business.

These opportunities involved building high performing Development and Quality Assurance teams from the ground up. The work also revolved around introducing processes and educating the business on how to become digital centric.

I'm a strong believer in a flat management structure with minimal or no title, as I understand that every individual brings something to the team - regardless of their years of experience.

I live by "open, honest and transparent" core values as I believe they are fundamental for any team to succeed.

My passion is for building - I spend my free time creating software, restoring old motorcycles, renovating or planning and building new furniture.

employment

Head of Dev & QA

Seven West Media, Sydney

12/2016-Current

- Delivered on time and under budget 7plus.com.au. Reached number #1 BVOD product within 12 months.
- All products are data rich in consistent manner to help making business and UX decisions.
- Functional MVP that held up against largest sporting and TV events such as Melbourne Cup.
- Researched and selected appropriate technologies and frameworks to ensure longevity and maintainability of the product.
- Built a large development and quality assurance team from the ground up to build and bring a lot of projects that were originally outsourced.

Digital Development Director

Pacific Magazines, Sydney

09/2015-12/2016

- All outsourced platforms were brought and delivered in-house.
- Delivered a number of e-commerce & content products new business ventures.
- Built an engineering team that developed as well as looked after DevOps and Infrastructure for the organisation.
- Pacific Mags continue to deliver great products based on our original platform.

Head of Digital Technology / Development Southern Cross Austereo, Sydney

06/2013-07/2015

- Transitioned all digital assets away from outsourcing partners to in-house team. (70+ radio and TV websites)
- · Looked after infrastructure as well as development of all websites and radio streams.
- Successfully rolled out HbbTV (FreeView+) to SCA. The only regional TV network to do it.
- Delivered a number of innovative solutions & ideas around online streaming unfortunately a lot were put on hold due to on-going court case with PPCA.

Software Developer

Amblique, Sydney

08/2012-06/2013

- Full stack developer working closely with clients to ensure that their e-commerce platforms and bringing forecasted yield. This involved bug fixes, release of new features and A/B testing.
- Maintaining and operating servers, databases, load balancers as well as on-call support. (Pre AWS/Cloud)
- One of the first developers in Australia to be DemandWare certified (e-commerce platform).

Consultant / Developer / Owner

Lemi Solutions, Sydney

2008-06/2013

- Consulting small to medium size companies on cost effective IT solutions and process improvements.
- Training staff on those new solutions and processes.
- Developing bespoke solutions if product that meet requirements didn't exist.
- Client support infrastructure as well as the day to day running of the system (backups, network, emails etc.)

Software Developer

DATACOM, NZ

02/2011-08/2012

- Worked on loan approval system with the goal to analyse and approve/decline requester within seconds.
- Worked on internal business management system (time sheets, invoicing, project management)
- Took over development and maintenance of SharePoint Intranet for the whole organisation.

education

BSc, Computer Science and Information Systems	Auckland
University, NZ	
	2011

Highlights

Computer Science Honour Roll	2010
Information Systems & Operations Honour Roll	2010

NCEA Level 3

Rangitoto College, NZ

2006

interests

PPL - Private pilot license

Currently working through my RPL and PPL pilot license.

Airhead - air cooled boxer typed engines / BMW series

I'm love motorcycle riding and recently I have been working on restoring/building/modifying BMW R100 "Airhead".

I would like to tour Australia on my R100 BMW.

Internet-of-things - smart-home/garden-care

I have worked with a friend of mine on an distributed, automated watering system that can detect

- · moisture levels
- humidity
- · temperature

System can handle multiple sensors, pumps and solenoids. It can automatically water set of plants or manually triggered from your phone. This system can take care of plants for over a month (limitation being size of water tank).

References

References available upon request.

This CV is available on

- Source code https://github.com/lemining/cv
- PDF http://llewandowski.com/detailed_cv.pdf
- HTML un-themed http://llewandowski.com
- · Hosted on GitHub Pages